-
  question: Which of the following is the largest carpal bone?
  answer:	A
  options:
    - capitate
    - hamate
    - scaphoid
    - triquetrum
-
  question: "The third metacarpal of the hand articulates with the:"
  answer:	D
  options:
    - lunate
    - scaphoid
    - hamate
    - capitate
-
  question: "The carpal bones articulate with the:"
  answer:	[ A ]
  options:
    - radius
    - ulna
    - phalanges
-
  question: Which of the following passes through the carpal tunnel?
  answer:	D
  options:
    - radial vein
    - radial nerve
    - median vein
    - median nerve
-
  question: "Flexing the fingers for a PA projection of the wrist causes which of the following:"
  answer:	B
  options:
    - placement of the carpal bones farther from the IR
    - placement of the carpal bones closer to the IR
    - less pain for the patient when the wrist is broken
    - greater resolution of the carpal interspaces
-
  question: "The central ray for a PA projection of the wrist is directed to the:"
  answer:	C
  options:
    - radiocarpal joint
    - scaphoid
    - midcarpal area
    - third CMC joint
-
  question: Which of the following should be in contact with the tabletop for a PA projection of the wrist?
  answer:	[ A, B, C ]
  options:
    - arm
    - axilla
    - forearm
-
  question: Which of the following projections would be used to better demonstrate the carpal interspaces?
  answer:	A
  options:
    - AP
    - PA
    - lateral
    - PA oblique with lateral rotation
-
  question: Which of the following central-ray angles is used for the lateral projection of the wrist?
  answer:	A
  options:
    - 0 degrees
    - 5 degrees
    - 7 degrees
    - 0 to 5 degrees
-
  question: "For a lateral projection of the wrist, the elbow must be flexed:"
  answer:	D
  options:
    - 0 degrees
    - 25 degrees
    - 45 degrees
    - 90 degrees
-
  question: Which of the following is the primary projection used to demonstrate anterior or posterior displacement of fractures of the hand or wrist?
  answer:	C
  options:
    - AP
    - PA
    - lateral
    - AP oblique
-
  question: "The PA oblique projection of the wrist in lateral rotation requires a wrist angulation of:"
  answer:	D
  options:
    - 25 degrees
    - 30 degrees
    - 40 degrees
    - 45 degrees
-
  question: For exact positioning of the PA oblique wrist, and to ensure duplication in follow-up examinations, which of the following is required?
  answer:	B
  options:
    - 30-degree foam wedge
    - 45-degree foam wedge
    - 2-inch block
    - 3-inch block
-
  question: "The central-ray angle for a PA oblique projection of the wrist is:"
  answer:	A
  options:
    - 0 degrees
    - 5 degrees
    - 12 degrees
    - 0 to 5 degrees
-
  question: Which of the following are well demonstrated on a PA oblique projection of the wrist?
  answer:	[ B, C ]
  options:
    - capitate
    - trapezium
    - scaphoid
-
  question: Which of the following projections clearly demonstrates the scaphoid?
  answer:	[ A, C ]
  options:
    - PA in ulnar flexion
    - PA oblique in lateral rotation
    - PA axial (Stecher method)
-
  question: "The PA projection of the wrist in ulnar deviation clearly demonstrates the:"
  answer:	D
  options:
    - trapezium
    - trapezoid
    - hamate
    - scaphoid
-
  question: Which of the following projections corrects foreshortening of the scaphoid?
  answer:	D
  options:
    - PA
    - PA oblique in lateral rotation
    - PA in radial deviation
    - PA in ulnar deviation
-
  question: "For the PA projection of the wrist in ulnar deviation, the central ray is angled:"
  answer:	A
  options:
    - 0 degrees
    - 5 degrees
    - 7 degrees
    - 5 to 7 degrees
-
  question: "For the PA projection of the wrist in ulnar deviation, the central ray is directed to the:"
  answer:	B
  options:
    - pisiform
    - scaphoid
    - radiocarpal joint
    - midcarpal area
-
  question: "The PA axial projection of the wrist (Stecher method) clearly demonstrates the:"
  answer:	C
  options:
    - lunate
    - capitate
    - scaphoid
    - distal row of carpal bones
-
  question: The IR must be elevated how many degrees for the PA axial projection of the wrist (Stecher method)?
  answer:	D
  options:
    - 5 degrees
    - 10 degrees
    - 15 degrees
    - 20 degrees
-
  question: "If the IR and wrist are placed flat on the table for the PA axial projection of the wrist (Stecher method), the central ray must be angled:"
  answer:	C
  options:
    - 5 degrees
    - 10 degrees
    - 20 degrees
    - 15 to 20 degrees
-
  question: "The central-ray angulation for the PA axial projection of the wrist (Stecher method) is:"
  answer:	A
  options:
    - 0 degrees
    - 5 degrees
    - 8 degrees
    - 10 degrees
-
  question: Which of the following methods is used to demonstrate the carpal canal?
  answer:	D
  options:
    - Stecher (PA axial)
    - Norgaard (AP oblique)
    - Lawrence (inferosuperior axial)
    - Gaynor-Hart (tangential)
-
  question: Which of the following tangential projections is used to demonstrate the carpal canal?
  answer:	[ B, C ]
  options:
    - axial
    - inferosuperior
    - superoinferior
-
  question: "The central-ray angulation for the tangential projection (inferosuperior) of demonstrating the carpal canal is:"
  answer:	C
  options:
    - 25 degrees
    - 30 degrees
    - 25 to 30 degrees
    - 35 to 45 degrees
-
  question: "For the AP projection of the forearm, the hand is:"
  answer:	A
  options:
    - supinated
    - pronated
    - placed in the lateral position
    - placed in a 45-degree oblique position
-
  question: How many degrees is the central ray angled for the AP forearm?
  answer:	A
  options:
    - 0
    - 5
    - 7
    - 5 to 7
-
  question: Which of the following joints should be clearly demonstrated on the AP projection of the forearm?
  answer:	[ A, B ]
  options:
    - wrist
    - elbow
    - proximal humerus
-
  question: "For the lateral projection of the forearm, the elbow should be flexed:"
  answer:	C
  options:
    - 45 degrees
    - 80 degrees
    - 90 degrees
    - 120 degrees
-
  question: The lateral projection of the forearm should clearly demonstrate which of the following?
  answer:	[ A, B, C ]
  options:
    - elbow joint
    - radius and ulna
    - proximal row of carpal bones
-
  question: Which of the following general procedures should be observed when performing x-ray examinations of the upper limb?
  answer:	[ A, C ]
  options:
    - remove rings and watches
    - have the patient change into a gown
    - use an R or L marker on each image
-
  question: Which of the following would not be needed for radiographic examinations of the upper limb?
  answer:	C
  options:
    - lead apron
    - sandbags
    - compression band
    - foam wedges
-
  question: A fracture of the distal radius with posterior displacement is known as a ____ fracture.
  answer:	A
  options:
    - Colle's
    - Smith's
    - Boxer's
    - Bennett's
-
  question: "The carpal located in the distal row, most medial is the:"
  answer:	A
  options:
    - hamate
    - capitate
    - pisiform
    - lunate
